riptapparel.com 2018-12-29

# RIPT Apparel Privacy Policy | RIPT Apparel

We can't guarantee delivery by Christmas for International orders placed after November 30th and Domestic orders placed after December 10th. 

Welcome to RIPT Apparel (“RIPT,” “we,” “us” and/or “our”). This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from https://www.riptapparel.com (the “Site”).

BY USING THE site, YOU ARE HEREBY CONSENTING TO OUR COLLECTION, USE, DISCLOSURE, TRANSFER AND STORAGE OF INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

**We collect Device Information using the following technologies:**

  1. “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
  2. “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.
  3. “Web beacons,” “tags,” and “pixels” are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

**Information you provide:**

Additionally when you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain information from you, including your name, email address, and phone number (collectively, “Contact Information”) as well as your billing address, shipping address, and payment information (including the last four digits of your credit card) (collectively, “Purchase Information”).  We refer to your Contact Information and Purchase Information collectively as “Order Information.” 

(Note also that some purchase mechanisms allow you to use Amazon Pay, Apple Pay, PayPal, or Google Pay.  In such instances, we do not collect any payment information.) 

When we talk about “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are talking both about Device Information and Order Information (unless we clearly state otherwise herein).

**HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We do not rent or sell your Personal Information without your permission.  However, we may use or share your Personal Information for purposes described herein.  

We store the Order Information internally and use the Order Information that we collect generally to fulfill any orders placed through the Site (including processing your payment information, arranging for shipping, and providing you with invoices and/or order confirmations).  Additionally, we use this Order Information to:

Communicate with you; Screen our orders for potential risk or fraud; and

When in line with the preferences you have shared with us, provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services.

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

We also use the Device Information for remarketing purposes.

In addition to the foregoing, we may also use your Personal Information for legitimate business purposes, including to:

  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business, our Site, and other products and services we offer
  * Tailor the content we display in our communications with you
  * Administer surveys and other market research
  * Comply with legal requirements, judicial process, and our company policies (including to verify users’ identity in connection with access or correction requests)
  * Protect against, identify, investigate, and respond to fraud, illegal activity (such as incidents of hacking or misuse of our Site), and claims and other liabilities, including by enforcing the terms and conditions that govern the services we provide

We may aggregate and/or de-identify any Personal Information that we collect, such that the information no longer identifies any specific individual. We may use, disclose and otherwise process such information for our own legitimate business purposes – including historical and statistical analysis and business planning – without restriction.

**SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above.  

For example, we use Shopify to power our online store (including the processing of payments)--you can read more about how Shopify uses your Personal Information here:  https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy. 

We share your Order Information with Breakout Commerce, Inc. d/b/a Gooten as part of our order fulfillment process--you can read more about how Gooten uses your Order Information here:  https://www.gooten.com/privacy-policy/.

We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site--you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here:  https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We share some of your Personal Information with our third party partners for marketing purposes.  In particular, we share your Order Information with Klaviyo Inc. for managing our email communications with you--you can read more about how Klaviyo uses your Order Information here:  https://www.klaviyo.com/privacy/policy. We also share your Contact Information with Facebook, Inc. for marketing and re-marketing purposes. 

We may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

We advertise on social networks to our customers and potential customers.

Finally, In the event that all or substantially all of RIPT Apparel LLC’s assets are acquired by a third party through sale, merger, or otherwise, Personal Information will be transferred to that third party, subject to the same terms and conditions of the then-existing Privacy Policy for the Site.  This section remains subject to any restrictions placed by third party vendors

Any third parties to whom we may disclose Personal Information (identified herein) may have their own privacy policies which describe how they use and disclose your Personal Information. Those policies will govern use, handling and disclosure of your personal information once we have shared it with those third parties as described in this Privacy Policy. If you want to learn more about their privacy practices, we encourage you to visit the websites of those third parties. 

**BEHAVIOURAL ADVERTISING**

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you.  For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

**You can opt out of targeted advertising by:**

**FACEBOOK** \- https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads

**GOOGLE** \- https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out portal at:  http://optout.aboutads.info/.

**DO NOT TRACK**

Please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

**COMMUNICATIONS**

When you provide us consent to do so (either upon placing an order or through our normal marketing communications), we will communicate with you through general marketing communications.  You must affirmatively opt-in to receive these communications before you receive them. 

Regardless of where you live, you may also opt-out of these marketing communications at any time by following the instructions provided in any marketing communication you receive.  Please note that even if you opt-out of receiving marketing communications, you may still receive-business related communications, such as transactional emails. 

**LINKING TO THIRD PARTY SERVICES**

When you click on links on our Site that take you to third-party websites, you will be subject to the third parties’ privacy policies.  While we support the protection of privacy on the Internet, we cannot be responsible for the actions of any third-party websites. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policies of any and every website you visit, whether you are linking from our Site or browsing on your own.

**SECURITY**

We strive to maintain internal controls and procedures to ensure that the Information you share with us is handled in a safe, secure and responsible manner.  We have security measures to help protect against loss, unauthorized access and alteration of the information in our control. We will only disclose such Information to employees and authorized service providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Policy.  Our databases are protected by physical, technical, and procedural measures that restrict access only to authorized persons in accordance with this Policy. Although no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure, and we cannot ensure against any loss, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, alteration, or destruction of data, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.  Nevertheless, we cannot and do not guarantee that information you post on or transmit to the Service will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.

**YOUR RIGHTS TO DATA - EUROPEAN CUSTOMERS**

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right (which you may do at any time), please contact us through the contact information below.  We will respond to any request as promptly as possible.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above.  

Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.  When we transfer your information to the U.S., we will protect it as described in this Privacy Policy. We nevertheless protect information from EU residents in accordance with applicable law.  

**DATA RETENTION**

When you place an order through the Site, we will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

**MINORS**

The Site is not intended for individuals under the age of 13.

**PROTECTING YOUR INFORMATION**

You have several options when deciding how you can best protect your Information.  One option is simply not to volunteer it. This approach would allow you to still visit our Site, although it may prevent you, for example, from placing orders.  The Federal Trade Commission’s website, www.ftc.gov, also offers useful information about how to protect personally identifiable information provided to a website.

**SUSPECTED VIOLATIONS**

If at any time you believe we have not adhered to the policies and principles set forth in this Privacy Policy, please notify us using the contact information provided below.  We will make all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly respond to your concerns.

**CHANGES**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.  We suggest that you review the current Privacy Policy at the start of each visit our Site. We will also notify you of material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting them to the Site or via email. Unless we clearly express otherwise, we will use Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Policy then in effect.  YOU ARE HEREBY ADVISED THAT YOUR CONTINUED USE OF OUR SITE CONSTITUTES YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF ANY AMENDMENTS TO AND THE MOST RECENT VERSION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please send an e-mail to support@riptapparel.com or write us: RIPT Apparel, LLC, 1341 W Fullerton Ave STE #263, Chicago, IL, 60614.

**CONTACT US**

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by email at support@riptapparel.com or by mail using the details provided below:

1341 W Fullerton Ave STE #263, Chicago, IL, 60614, United States

**This privacy policy was last modified on May 18, 2018.**
